so funny how that happens funny how that
happens you know and then I I want to go
back to what I wrote because I was
thinking and I don't know if Matias was
was was responding to my poster he was
posting something else but you know I
realized that cohesion coherence
distinction is one that is so often
missed and and it isn't that cohesion
isn't useful or valuable but but that it
was so much of the learning of of the
symposium and in that period of time
yeah and I think what's interesting is
you see the broad range of cultures the
Tooth the de to the spectrum of cultures
that we have that we're working with so
on the one hand you have the legacy
corporations the legacy organizations
where there's too much individual
contribution there's too much
competition and they don't know how to
build teens right and so they have you
know so agile comes along and they make
everything team based team centered and
they create these really cool teams that
are very cohesive and then the unit that
it's protected is the team right and so
this sense is being improvement maybe
its not an improvement but this middle
range this notion of coherence is the
ability to move in and out of what we
call locations and settle into a team
interaction as quickly as possible
without then creating a team that is
protective and then you get the politics
of inclusion and exclusion new people
can't quite get on board and you know so
this is something that general
McChrystal about in his book team of
teams
as they knew how to have hierarchical
chain of commands and they knew how to
create these great teams like the seals
right these SWAT teams and he talks
about what had to uh all the different
things that had to be emplaced for that
seal team that saved that captain from
those pirates you know it was a movie
made by Tom Hanks right and they had
they had to execute five shots all at
the same time with two boats going up
and down in people moving in or else if
one person had been left alive they they
would have killed Tom Hanks you know and
so he talked about how they experience
that is one organism so that's really
deep cohesion right but it also in the
book talks about how those teams can
never get along with other teams you
know right right and and that so the
unit of the bounded unit becomes the
team so that could be better but it's
still a bounded unit so we try to look
at that and look at the politics of
inclusion and exclusion and say we can
even do better than that so this is a
big reason why we moved to the notion of
location and it could be that you you
know a team is a location and you could
have just a very cohesive team as a
location but ideally you have lots of
different locations and people self
organized into different teams to evolve
those locations like you know like like
different people going to different
people's houses for a barbecue that
it'll self organized in different ways
who cooks who this who gets drunk who
plays baseball watches TV you know right
I'm them and yet
the end of the day there are some groups
of people that are tighter than other
groups of people but that would be kind
of the idea there and and so broadly one
of the mistakes that people doing the
teal organizations or alternative
organizations is that they're just
they're just switching the context and
making the same mistakes right so
they're switching to a team context but
they're not they're making the same
mistakes they're not eliminating the
politics of inclusion and exclusion now
ideally you know that's an idealist
position you can't eliminate it entirely
but you can make it transparent in
teamwork in your team-building exercises
and your facilitation so it can tap into
higher performance so uh yeah so that
one little distinction is this is like a
big deal
you